Taron Vardanyan Software Engineer

+37491578212 tarokavardanyan@gmail.com

Versatile Front-end Developer with 3 years of experience designing, developing and managing complex sites and internal frameworks. Specializes in ReactJS and responsive design. Have experience with online learning systems, also with project management tools. Right now I'm working on an AI-based social network project.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of **Engineering**

National Polytechnic University of Armenia 2013-2019

Master of Engineering

National Polytechnic University of Armenia 2019-2021

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

SoftConstruct/HOORY · Jul 2021 - current

In this position, I am working on Social media platform which will allow users who have a virtual assistant to train them and do some useful research related to their interests and profession. In other words, this project is for managing and saving useful information as knowledge, which can be sold or shared with the network. The team is working with Agile Scrum System .On the client-side, we use Lerna, React.js(SPA), Next.js, Yarn workspaces, Mobx, MST, Context, Styled Components, and Framer Motion. And as a software engineer, my responsibility is to connect and work with the web design team to discuss the UI/UX templates, write reusable code, and keep connected to be able to discuss a data managing system not only for the client but also for back end and server-

Software Engineer

Esterox · Feb 2020 - Jul 2021

In this position, I was working on an Agile Performance Management application, which was created from scratch using the React, is library. Customer preferred to create an application as SPA. From the client-side was used React.js, SCSS, PWA, Antd, React Transition Group.

Junior Front End Developer

Esterox · Aug 2019 - Feb 2020

In this role, I worked on online learning platforms. The project's back end was in PHP, and the client-side was generated statically with PHP also. As a junior frontend developer, my responsibility was to add new JS features inside of a project, resolve UI/UX bugs, and improve the old and deprecated JS code. In this project, I was working with CSS and JS. And because of that, the page was generated on a PHP server, and the major part of my work was managing and creating features that will manipulate the DOM tree.

Junior HTML/CSS Markup Developer

Esterox · May 2019 - Aug 2019

As a junior front-end developer, I created web sites markup structures and added styles to them using CSS, SCSS, LESS. Also, I was responsible for web page responsiveness and flexibility, and for resolving browsers' compatibility problems.